(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're looking
at some more romance.
- We're talking about dating.
- Dating exactly.
- And not only dating but asking someone
to become your boyfriend or girlfriend.
- Yep, that's true.
And so we're gonna be focusing on
language to express your romantic feelings.
And also maybe some phrases
you can use to ask someone out.
- Very good.
- So I'm sure you guys
are excited about this one.
So let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, you're really, where is everyone?
- Well, I told them not to come.
I made a reservation
just for the two of us.
I thought we could have a
quiet evening all to ourselves.
- Oh, why?
- Jennifer, there's
something I wanna ask you.
- Sure, what is it?
- Mm, okay, here's the thing.
I've always seen you as more than
just a friend and I can't take it anymore.
I know you better than anyone.
I know the pros and
cons of your personality.
I even know what side of the bed is yours.
I think we would be
great together, don't you?
- Are you serious?
We've been friends for years.
We can't just change that overnight.
- I know.
I never had the guts
to tell you until today.
So what do you say?
Are you willing to give me a shot?
Ah, ah, ah.
- All right, I wonder,
is she going to say yes?
- I don't know, she
seems a little bit confused.
- Mm, well, I guess it's
always strange when your best
friend suddenly wants to be
your boyfriend or girlfriend.
- It does happen though, it does happen.
So why don't we take a look
at some of the vocabulary
that was used in this
dialogue to express these
feelings and let's start
with fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
Okay, so we're doing things
a little differently today.
We're looking at phrases
and not just vocabulary words.
So to use some wonderful
phrases to ask her to be his
boyfriend and he started
with this, here's the thing.
- Here's the thing, here's the thing.
- All right, that's a very
strange phrase, here's the thing.
It's giving her something.
- Not quite, he's not giving her an object
but he's giving her some information.
- Okay, so it's a very
common way to start an idea.
- That's right, you're
about to tell the person
the main problem or the
main piece of information, right?
So you would start with, here's
the thing and then start explaining.
- Okay, why don't we do an example?
For example, you could
say, all right, here's the thing.
People don't like you.
- All right, well, I hope
they don't say that to me.
But another example,
Marco, here's the thing.
We're behind in our podcasting,
we have to work over time.
- Okay, so the main idea.
- Yep, very good.
Moving on to our next phrase.
- He said, I can't take it.
I can't take it anymore.
- I can't take it anymore.
- So he can't take it anymore, take what?
Well, why don't we find out
by listening to some examples?
- Example one.
- The man next door has been sold out.
I can't take it anymore.
- Example two.
- My boss always yields at me.
I can't take it anymore.
- Example three.
- I can't take it anymore.
I'm going to quit.
- All right, so basically is you can't
stand it, you can't tolerate it anymore.
- Exactly, this is a phrase we
use when we are really frustrated.
- But yeah, when we're frustrated or
when we just can't handle it anymore.
And well, after he
finished his declaration of
love, she responded by
saying, are you serious?
- Are you serious?
Are you serious?
- Okay, so what does she mean?
She's just saying, really?
- Exactly, it's another
way of saying really?
- Yeah, so this is a phrase that's
really, it's quite informal, isn't it?
- Yeah, I guess you wouldn't
use it in a business context.
- No, and it's also something
that's used mostly by younger people.
- Right, if you say something
that's amazing or that's
incredible, hard to believe,
you might get this response.
- Are you serious?
- Right.
- So he is very serious, but he confessed
that he never had the guts to tell her.
- Mm-hmm, have the guts.
- I never had the guts to tell you.
- I never had the guts.
- All right, so to have guts, that's
to be brave, to be brave, courageous.
- Yep.
- So we have some
examples of how we would use
guts in different
situations, so let's listen.
- Example one.
- I don't have the guts to go, sky diving.
- Example two.
- I don't have the guts to give a speech.
- Example three.
- I've never had the
guts to say no to my boss.
- All right, so to have
the guts to do something,
hey, but Marco, this word
guts is an interesting one.
- Yes, it is because guts can
also mean your internal organs.
- Like your stomach and
your intestines and your lungs.
- Exactly, those are your guts.
- Yep, so when you have
guts, you're really brave.
- Exactly, you're courageous.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right, very good.
Why don't we listen to the
dialogue for the second time?
We're gonna slow it down
a little bit and we'll come
back and look at some
phrases and putting it together.
- Hey, you're early, where's everyone?
- Well, I told them not to come.
I made a reservation
just for the two of us.
I thought we could have a
quiet evening all to ourselves.
- Oh, why?
- Jennifer, there's
something I want to ask you.
- Sure, what is it?
- Mm, okay, here's the thing.
I've always seen you as more than
just a friend and I can't take it anymore.
I know you better than anyone.
I know the pros and
cons of your personality.
I even know what side of the bed is yours.
I think we would be
great together, don't you?
Are you serious?
We've been friends for years.
We can't just change that overnight.
- I know.
I've never had the guts
to tell you until today.
So, what do you say?
Are you willing to give me a shot?
- I, I.
(upbeat music)
All right, so that's a
little bit clearer this time.
But while I was listening, I
noticed that there's some more
great phrases that you can use
together with different words.
So, let's look at those
now and putting it together.
Putting it together.
- All right, let's take
a look at the first one.
He said, "I made a reservation
just for the two of us.
" The two of us,
just the two of us.
So, just the two of us.
Quite simply, it means
you and me, just us, right?
- Right, just us.
So, why is this phrase important?
- I think it's a great way to
show the idea of only us, right?
- Right.
- And we can use it together
with any number we want.
- So, what about the four of us?
- Mm-hmm.
- Just the four of us.
- Okay.
- Just the eight of us.
- So, so it suggests the idea of only us.
- Okay.
- So, he made the reservation
just for the two of us
because he thought they
could have a quiet evening
all to ourselves, all to
ourselves, all to ourselves.
- If you have something all to yourself
or we have something all to ourselves.
- We have that thing all alone.
We don't have to share it.
- We don't share, very good.
So, I guess you can say,
my parents are out of town.
So, I have the apartment, I
have the house all to myself.
- Mm-hmm.
- Or even she wants to
eat the cake all to herself.
- Very good, so that's a very good phrase.
- And you can use it with any pronoun.
- Well, so the guy
is explaining that I've
always seen you as
more than just a friend.
- I've always seen you as.
- So, basically, is the perception or
the way you consider that person?
- The way you think about that person.
- So, I can say, I've always
seen you as a good friend.
- I've always seen you as a leader.
Okay, so our last phrase is also the
last thing we heard in the dialogue.
He said, "Are you
willing to give me a shot?
" - Are you willing to give
me a shot, to give me a shot?
- Give me a shot.
- All right, I think we
have some more examples
of how we could use, give me a shot
in different situations, so let's listen.
- Example one.
I know I can do this drawing better.
Just give me a shot.
Example two.
- The HR manager wasn't gonna hire
me, but he decided to give me a shot.
- Okay, so when you give someone
a shot, you take a chance, right?
- Give that person or give an opportunity.
- All right, so we don't know if she will
give him a shot or not,
but why don't we listen
to the dialogue once more
to hear these phrases in action.
- Okay, you're really, where is everyone?
- Well, I told them not to come.
I made a reservation
just for the two of us.
I thought we could have a
quiet evening all to ourselves.
- Oh, why?
- Jennifer, there's
something I wanna ask you.
- Sure, what is it?
- Okay, here's the thing.
I've always seen you as more than
just a friend and I can't take it anymore.
I know you better than anyone.
I know the pros and
cons of your personality.
I even know what side of the bed is yours.
And I think we would be
great together, don't you?
- Are you serious?
We've been friends for years.
We can't just change that overnight.
- I know.
I never had the guts
to tell you until today.
So what do you say?
Are you willing to give me a shot?
- Aah, aah, aah.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so an interesting dialogue,
and it opens up a cultural point.
- That's right.
So in the dialogue, the guy was asking
her if she would be his girlfriend, right?
- Right, but I guess it's not very common
among adults at least in
English speaking countries.
- Yeah, we don't say like, okay, so
please, will you be my boyfriend now?
- Right, right, right.
- You would do that maybe in high school.
- Yeah, but even then, I
think it's still a little funny.
I think for us, when we
start to have romantic
relationships, it just sort
of happens naturally, right?
You never really have this
conversation, will you be my boyfriend?
- Right, I guess
afterwards, you just start
talking about other things,
which you just consider
that you guys are already
boyfriend and girlfriend.
But there's no official starting point.
- There's no official point that says,
okay, now we are boyfriend and girlfriend.
- Yep, which is interesting
because in other countries,
they do go through the formality of
asking somebody to become their boyfriend.
- Yeah, but even like 20 or 30 years ago
in English speaking
countries, you would do this.
- Oh yeah, of course.
- And it was called going steady.
- Going steady.
- So you would ask, well,
you go steady with me.
- That means let's become a stable couple.
- Exactly.
- All right, so we wanna hear your stories
and well, how do you do it in your country?
Do you ask someone out?
Do you maybe just give them the
first kiss and that's in automatic, yes?
- Well, I don't know, but I'm looking
forward to hearing from our listeners.
So guys, check out
our website, EnglishPod.
com.
You can leave your
questions and comments there.
- All right, we'll see you guys there.
And until next time, goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)